When you or someone in your family falls ill, do
you
think four times before getting treatment in a good hospital? If you
go there, it will be a very expensive
hospital and you will go to that doctor
even if he is the best doctor but the
treatment is expensive and his fees are expensive, so
you do not want to go there. Do you
compromise in getting your treatment done? Suppose
your son or your parents are admitted in the hospital
and they need a lot of money there
and if you go to a cheap hospital
and something happens to them, then
this thought will come to your mind, as in the movie, if
something happens then we will burn the world. There is
no need to burn the world, you need a proper health
insurance so that he can recover.
Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajput.
I am the founder of Family First Financial
Services. I have been working in the corporate sector for 13 years
and today I am presenting to you the
best health
insurance policy of ICICI Lombard Max Protect, launched on 5th December
2023, where you can get insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore, 2 crore, 3
crore, 5 crore, 10 crore or unlimited  You
can take it and that too at a very
low premium. In this video, I have
explained this in detail. You should
watch the entire video and if you like my video, you will
see my youtube4 written on it. Click on it.
If you
want to watch the video in any other language other than Hindi, like English,
Tamil, Telugu, Gujarati, then you
can select the subtitle there.
In which language do you want the subtitles? Now let's
see the speciality of this plan. The
biggest thing here is that you will get unlimited
insurance cover. If you also want to take one crore, two crore, three
crore, five crore, ten crore unlimited
insurance cover, then
you will get it in this policy, that too at an affordable
price. And here you will
also get different options whether you want to take the classic
version or the premium plan. The
features of both are also different and the premium is also
different. So, you are also given options as to which
plan you should take according to your need.
Now, when you take a health insurance
policy or
while taking this policy, what things should you keep in mind
or why should you take this plan? The
biggest thing is that inflation, the rate of
medical insurance in India  The
inflation rate of healthcare is at 14,
which means that the cost of medical care doubles every five years,
which means that the treatment that is being done today,
you will have to pay double for it in 2028. So
you don't
want to buy insurance again and again, or at that time the
insurance will be expensive, the premiums will also be expensive, the
treatment will also be expensive, so you
should buy a policy now and
beat inflation etc. because the
insurance cover in this is minimum Rs 1 crore, so
it will easily beat inflation.
Secondly, there is no coverage limit worry.
What happens now is that when it comes to getting admitted in the hospital, the
customer gets a little
worried that whether I should
go to this hospital or not, my
insurance cover here is only of Rs 5 lakh, now the
bill there is more, Rs 7 lakh, Rs 10 lakh, Rs
15 lakh, if I go to an expensive hospital then
what will happen, from where will I pay it, so
here you do not need to worry about
how big your bill is
because the company  It will pay you because here
you are getting a big insurance cover at a low cost. The
third big thing is that
you can access good healthcare. Let's say you fall
ill. Now there are
many hospitals near you, but among them there is
one excellent hospital, but you are
thinking that if I go there, the
bill will be very high. It is such an expensive hospital, there are
expensive doctors, how will I manage it. So there is
no need for you to worry after taking this policy because even if the
hospital is very expensive, your insurance cover is
quite good, so you can get
treatment in the best hospital and get
cured.
Coverage for various medical expenses,
pre-hospitalization, post-hospitalization,
modern treatment, many things are
covered in this plan. Worldwide cover is also
available. If you take its premium option, then
you can also give the benefit of insurance cover up to ₹ 1 crore worldwide.
Many times, people from India go abroad to visit
their relatives, go to
meet their parents or go to
meet their son, then travel
insurance or home insurance may be insufficient for you, so
if you
have this insurance, then up to 3 crores  Even if you fall ill,
treatment up to ₹ crore will be covered
there. Pre and post
worldwide treatment is not covered there, only in-
patient treatment is covered. If we
talk about reset benefit, which
in other words can be called restore benefit, then
you will get this unlimited times,
suppose you took a policy of 1 crore, fell ill,
added 1 crore, then up to 1 crore will be
automatically restored, there is
no need to pay a separate premium for that, so
you will get this reset benefit unlimited times
and you will also get cumulative bonus on 20, in the
year in which your claim will not come,
that year your insurance cover will increase by 20, that is, at least 20 lakhs.
In this policy, if you get admitted in the hospital, then the
expenses of the cover for 2 months before that and 6 months after that will be covered.
You can take insurance from 1 crore to 10 crore. You
can also take unlimited insurance cover, you will get 20 per
no.  You will also get a claim bonus. If you want to get AYUSH treatment or
Ayurvedic treatment, then
that will also be covered under this policy.
Donor
expenses will also be covered under this policy.
If you suffer from any such disease in
which it becomes difficult to move from one place to another
or there are
no vacant beds in the hospital, then if you want to get treatment at home, then the
minimum period is 10 days. If you
get treatment at home, then these
expenses will also be covered for you. Let's talk about
obesity-related
bariatric surgery.
If the doctor recommends weight loss surgery, then the
expenses of weight loss surgery will also be covered under this policy.
You can also avail benefits of modern treatments up to ₹ crore in this policy,
like robotic surgery.
Talking about domestic road ambulance,
you can also avail benefits of road ambulance up to ₹ 1000000. The
company will
provide you unlimited
tele-consultation for the ambulance expenses up to ₹ 10000 in this policy.  You can take it if you want to
talk to a doctor by talking to him on the phone, you
can avail his services unlimited times.
I have already talked about unlimited restore,
suppose your basic term is completed
then you will get a restore benefit,
meaning 1 crore. If you have spent the entire 1 crore in your policy then the
company will give you 1 crore again,
this is called reset benefit,
restore benefit and if we talk about value added
services, you will also be given in this policy, all these
benefits are there
in the classic policy, there are two options, one is the
classic plan and the other is the premium plan,
I have already explained the benefits to you in the classic, in the
premium, along with the
classic, you will get the features, one is
world wide cover, you can get
treatment all over the world, you can get in-
patient treatment worldwide with insurance cover up to ₹ crore, you will
also get air ambulance cover up to some extent, so that if you have to be
taken from one place to another through air ambulance, plane or plane,
probably in India, then you will get this benefit there also,
home care  Treatment will also be
covered up to ₹ lakh in this policy. Claim
protector means consumable one-time
use and throw expenses
like PP kit, gloves, mask, cotton etc.
You can also avail the benefit of such things
in this policy.
You will also get health checkup up to ₹ 1000000.
For health checkup, your age must be at least 21
years and if you
want to take second opinion related to 33 critical illnesses,
then you will also be able to take second opinion. As for
optional benefits in the policy,
if you downgrade the room rent here,
suppose you want to change the room and
come to a single AC private room, then
you will get a discount here. If you have
taken the classic option, then if you
downgrade and come to a single AC private room, then
you will get a discount there. If you have taken the classic option, then you will have to pay
pre-agistration in the premium.
Now let's talk zone wise,
four different zones have been given, A, B, C, D.
If we talk about zone A, then there are Delhi, Mumbai and
Daman.  This is Gujarat, Ahmedabad.
Ahmedabad and Surat in Gujarat are
covered here, which will come in Zone A.
In Zone B, you will find Pune, Kolkata, Ahmedabad, Surat,
except Bangalore, Chennai, Andhra Pradesh
in Zone B. Zone C has
Rest of India for you, which includes Jammu and
Kashmir, Ladakh, Lakshadweep, Kerala.
So, you can see here on the side
which zone you are coming in.
Your premium will be as per that zone.
Plus, suppose you get treatment done in a higher zone
and you will have to pay 1%,
suppose you are in Zone B and you
go to a city in Zone A for treatment. Suppose
you live in Chhattisgarh and you have to
go to Delhi for treatment, then
you will have to pay up to 100% of the claim that comes from your pocket. You will have to pay it
as payment. Talking about the
term and conditions, I have already
told you many times about the insurance cover.
In this policy, you will get insurance cover of 1 crore, 2 crore, 3 crore, 5
crore, 10 crore and unlimited time.
Talking about eligibility, this policy is for a person between 6 years to 55 years of age.
Child can purchase from 91 days to 5 years It can be covered in this
Who will be covered under the flat policy Grandfather Grand Mother
Father in law Spouse Son Daughter Brother Father Mother
Now if we talk about the
waiting period in pre-assisting disease,
then
your waiting period related to pre-assisting disease will be 4 years and for
specific illness you will have a
waiting period of 2 years like cataract,
hernia, stone for this type of disease there will be a
waiting period of 2 years For bariatric surgery you have a waiting period of 3 years and for the
premium policy which is covered worldwide you will
also have a waiting period of 2 years
Talking about the room rent limit,
you will get all rooms except
suites
category If you downsize and
come in single SC or single private room then
you will
get a discount free here If we talk about the policy period in classic plan then
you can take a policy of 1 year,
2 years and 3 years as well
if  If you take it for two years or nine years,
you will also get a discount of Rs 10 or Rs 15. We were
talking about zone wise
classification, so you have been given four options of Zone A, B, CD
and the payment for different zones has
also been told to you. Now let's talk about the
premium, if you
take the classic plan and with GST,
you can see the premium here, if
suppose someone's age is up to 25 years, then
you will
get a health insurance cover of Rs 1 crore for Rs 15,352 including GST of Rs 18.
If you want to take an insurance cover of Rs 10 crore, then it will cost
you Rs 1 and if you
want to take unlimited insurance cover and do
not want to keep any limit, then
you can also take unlimited insurance cover for Rs 62. Rest,
you
can see the age wise premium here. Let's see the premium
plan where you get world wide cover,
air ambulance, home care, claim protector,
health checkup and second opinion,
extra in critical illness which will be from
classic. The premium here is yours.
If you are 25 years old then you will be
able to get insurance of 1 crore for 19141,
you will get insurance of 10 crore for 2497 and
you
can get unlimited insurance cover for 26600. Now if the
plans of this category are compared with each other
then Care Advantage is a policy of
Care Health Insurance so if we
compare it with that then if we are
taking a policy of one year in ICICI then I have taken it without GST
sorry with GST here it is of two adults husband
and wife till the age of 25 years then
insurance cover of 1 crore for ₹ 380
in ICICI for two persons will
come for 2380, in the same Care Advantage you will get 2634,
if your age is 35 years then
ICICI will give you 23259 and in 2463 if
you are 40 years then
ICICI will provide you 2968 and
in 8450 you will get Care Advantage  You will get the advantage if
your age is 45, then ECIC is giving
you insurance cover of Rs. 1 crore for Rs. 33, and
for husband and wife, you
can also see that the premium of this plan is comparatively much
less than other plans.
Talking about cancellation in this policy,
suppose you want to cancel this policy,
if you have taken a policy for one year, for
two years or for three years, if you
surrender in the first month, you
cancel the policy and
you will get a refund of one year policy. Even if
you have taken a one year policy for two years,
you will get 80% of your premium
back for one year. If you
cancel between one to three months, you will
get 60% in a one year policy, 70%
in a two year policy and 75%
in a three year policy. In this way, you
can also see the remaining percentage that when you cancel,
how much percentage will you get back.  You will
get money. Talking about the free look period,
you have been given a free look period of 15 days.
If you want to cancel the policy,
you can do so and
get a refund. During this period, a small
amount will be deducted from your
insurance cost and the
remaining amount will be refunded. This will be the
free look period for your
policy.